Guide to the Stanford Museum Collection
Stanford University Library
- Museum objects
  - Photograph; framed, glass, BW; Inner Quad, Early Years, Horse and Buggy.. frame 29x37cm, image 27x34 cm. [REMOVED 2/2006], ARCH-AM-2000-297 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, BW; Memorial Arch, pre 1906. frame 30x36 cm, image 27x35 cm. [REMOVED 2/2006], ARCH-AM-2000-296 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, BW; Mother of Mrs. David Jacks; Mrs. Frederica Romie nee Maria Magdealana Frohn. Signed C. Porsch. frame 65x51 (gold), image 56x42 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-305 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, BW; Peninsula Railway with ad for Palo Alto real estate [REMOVED 2/2006], ARCH-AM-2000-295 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, BW; Students in Academic gowns on inner Quad, c. 1900's. frame 28x44, image 25x40 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-302 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, BW. "twin redwood trees in 1883. San Francisco Creek, country line-- Menlo Park and Palo Alto. frame 51x38 cm, image 49x36 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-303 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, BW. David Starr Jordan, profile. frame 54x23, image 33x24 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-288 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, BW. Leland Stanford's home, Palo Alto, 1905-. frame 40x49 cm, image 24x33 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-287 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, front view Quad pre 1906, oblique, sepia. frame 55x97 cm, image 45x88 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-281 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, sepia, Twin Redwood Tress, San Francisquita Creek and Menlo Park. frame 56x43 cm, image 51x38 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-282 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, sepia; View of Quad from front, pre 1906. frame 74x38cm, image 21x17cm., ARCH-AM-2000-299 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, sepia. Football Team, Class of 1895. frame 57x63, image 26x32 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-309 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, sepia. Psychology Dept. April 18, 1906. View of earthquake damage. Quad bldg. frame 47x39 cm, image ?., ARCH-AM-2000-300 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass, tinted. Golden Spike Ceremony. frame 68x90, image 38x71 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-326 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; framed, glass. Student group, circa 1900's. frame 16x65, image 28x48 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-291 (Box 1)
  - Photograph; tinted, framed, glass. Golden Spike Ceremony. frame 69x88 cm, image 47x67., ARCH-AM-2000-322 (Box 1)
  - Photograph: Framed: 61X47X5 cm. BW Photo 49X37 cm. O.L.Elliot, Registrar, 1891-1925., ARCH-AM-2000-153 (Box 1)
  - Photograph. Leland Stanford, Jr. 14 X 9 cm photo. 25 X 20 cm frame under glass- Purple frame. L.S. Jr. with derby hat cane in left hand., ARCH-AM-2000-119 (Box 1)
  - Photograph. Leland Stanford, Jr. 13X9 cm 18X13 cm frame. On convex surface. Fold Frame, no glass. Straight head portrait., ARCH-AM-2000-121 (Box 1)
  - Photograph. Man with beard and lady. 29X24 cm image; 43X37 cm frame. Oval on ceramic surface, by "Fr. Jull Dresden", ARCH-AM-2000-123 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, framed, Delta Gamma (BW Glass) members 1914-1915. frame 36x48, individual photos 10x8cm., ARCH-AM-2000-328 (Box 1)
  - Picture frame (only) 42X49 cm. Gold leaf painted on frame, 4 cm wide., ARCH-AM-2000-176 (Box 1)
  - Picture frame (only), gold leaf (33 x 26 cm). Note re American Chapel in Paris where Leland jr. reposed., ARCH-AM-2000-175 (Box 1)
  - Picture Frame 50X60 cm gold edge and purple liner., ARCH-AM-2000-166 (Box 1)
  - Piece of '95 oak (slice) with engraving "Ninety-Five Oak", ARCH-AM-2000-038 (Box 1)
  - Piece of mosaic from Mem. Church. 14 x 5.5 x 4.5 cm. Green and gold pieces., ARCH-AM-1984-54 (Box 1)
  - Piece of mosaic from Memorial Church ('06 debris). Found by Lyman children on campus (where current SCRA pool is). [gold and purple pieces, 3.5 in. square], ARCH-AM-2003-006 (Box 1)
  - Piece of mosaic from Memorial Church, collected after the 1906 earthquake by Arthur E. Bessey - red, blue and gold mosaic pieces, ARCH-AM-2005-036 (Box 1)
  - Piece of mosaic from Memorial Church, fallen in 1906 earthquake and picked up by Ed Naldrett, ARCH-AM-2005-040 (Box 1)
    gold pieces, some in form of arch, with blue pieces below arch. 5 x 2.5 inches and 2.5 inches thick
  - piece of mosaic from Memorial Church, pieces arranged in "stripes" - gold, blue, bold, red, gold, red [6.5 in at widest], ARCH-AM-2007-019 (Box 1)
  - Piece of the Matterhorn, obtained by David Starr Jordan on his ascent of the mountain; class case 7 x 5 x 5 inches, ARCH-AM-2000-028 (Box 1)
  - Pieces from Church mosaic, ARCH-AM-1996-11 (Box 1)
    96-11.1 Mosaic piece 28 x 23 cm 96-11.2 Mosaic piece, related to 11.1, 31 x 32 cm
  - Pieces of original tile work from base of the Angel of Grief statue and plaster cast for the outstretched arm of the statue, ARCH-AM-2000-030 (Box 1)
    2000-030.1 original tile (2 chunks) 2000-030.2 Cast of arm
  - Pin (3 in. diameter) - "Once an Indian Always an Indian", ARCH-AM-1992-13 (Box 1)
  - Pin: Yosemite Winter Club, in the shap of a ski. "V.W. R." on the reverse (maker?). Possibly brass; gold-toned in color, ARCH-AM-2008-010 (Box 1)
  - Pins (2) owned by Fred Ludeke (class of 1924), ARCH-AM-2005-015 (Box 1)
    2005-015.1 Axe Committee pin 2005-015.2 Skull and Snakes pin
  - Pint Glass (1): "Haas Center For Public Service Stanford" Mugs (2): "Stanford Centennial Thanks You!"; "Stanford Red Barn", ARCH-AM-2009-035 (Box 1)
    2009-035.1 "Haas Center For Public Service Stanford" Pint Glass 2009-035.2 "Stanford Centennial Thanks You!" Mug 2009-035.3 "Stanford Red Barn" Mug
  - Plaque "Leland Stanford Junior University", ARCH-AM-1978-01 (Box 1)
  - Plaque (brass?) in honor of Leonard Daniels Ellis, class of 1934, specifically in honor of the perpetual scholarship set up by his parents Mr. Mrs. Leonard A. Ellis. Ellis died on July 31, 1933. 2.75 x 4 in., ARCH-AM-2007-029 (Box 1)
  - Plaque for 3 scholarship donations to S.U. for "Most Valuable Player" awards in 3 football games 1994 (Brian Manning, Steve Stenstrom, Anthony Bookman), ARCH-AM-2001-28 (Box 1)
  - Plaque honoring Orrin Leslie Elliot, ARCH-AM-2000-024 (Box 1)
  - Plaque honoring Robert Edouard Pellissier (WWI), ARCH-AM-2000-006 (Box 1)
  - Plaque honoring Stanford Ambulance Corps, Robert Edouard Pellissier, ARCH-AM-2000-030 (Box 1)
  - Plaque honoring W. Herrman G. Ross, ARCH-AM-2000-029 (Box 1)
  - Plaque of photographs of the earth and Space Shuttle, U.S. flag and patch, flown on Challenger., ARCH-AM-1984-18 (Box 1)
  - Plaque on Football team 1992 PAC-10 co-champions and 1993 Blockbuster Bowl Champions, includes photo of team, ARCH-AM-2001-29 (Box 1)
  - plaque, "Presented to Stanford University in Appreciation for cooperation... Inter-American Defense College, May 12, 1982.", ARCH-AM-1984-07 (Box 1)
  - Plaque, Metal on wood. 69X56 cm. National ROTC rifle Match, 1956. 3rd place to stanford Team, ARCH-AM-2000-189 (Box 1)
  - Plaque, relief, metal of David Starr Jordan, profile. 42x30 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-310 (Box 1)
  - Plaque: in honor of Howie Dallmar on 1988 induction to S.U. Sports Hall of Fame, ARCH-AM-1995-02 (Box 1)
  - Plaque: membership certificate for S.U. in American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education - 1948, ARCH-AM-1995-33 (Box 1)
  - Plaque: Monterey Rugby Tournament. 1st Place 1965 Carmel California Stanford University. Wooden base., ARCH-AM-2006-035 (Box 1)
  - plaque: Walk to Cure Diabetes 2002 Platinum Award presented to Stanford University. Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation., ARCH-AM-2006-028 (Box 1)
  - Plaster bas relief of Arthur Schawlow by Jennifer Clinton [or possibly Hinton], mounted on black plastic. From Laser Inst. Am - medal, 1985, ARCH-AM-2006-023 (Box 1)
  - Plaster chunks showing original wall color in Knoll's entry lobby, ARCH-AM-2005-028 (Box 1)
  - Plaster Relief of Luther Burbank. 22x15x1cm. Profile, white., ARCH-AM-2000-249 (Box 1)
  - Plaster wall pieces from Encina basement (south) showing paint colors, ARCH-AM-1997-024 (Box 1)
  - Plastic Box with ticker-tape style invitation cellophane strips, ARCH-AM-1994-03 (Box 1)
  - Plastic decal of "L'il Injun" caricature by Jack Dixon, ARCH-AM-2002-39 (Box 1)
  - Plastic hardhat with label "Final Salute to Stanford Stadium November 26, 2005" - memento given out at game, ARCH-AM-2005-044 (Box 1)
    2 additional hats (gift of Dick and Sue Blois) added 9/28/07
  - Plastic paper weight: Distaff Club silver anniversary, 1976, ARCH-AM-1992-02 (Box 1)
  - Plastic relief rendition of the arcade and quadrangle, painted yellow and brown, 10x6.5, ARCH-AM-1983-12 (Box 1)
  - Plug Ugly [class of 1910] 1909. Elaborately painted with coed on top, LSJU seal on front, ARCH-AM-1981-12 (Box 1)
  - Plug Ugly Class of 1911. Decorations: chemist saying Eureka! on top; Stanford seal, 1911 Chem Geol, and Encina Club around sides; Stanford eleven Wah Whoo S.U. on upper edge of brim. Removable metal band inside hat, ARCH-AM-2005-011 (Box 1)
  - Plug Ugly Class of 1912. Decorations: arcade arches on top; University seal, student surveyor, Encina Club along sides; Stanford Stanford 12 Hurrah! Hurroo! 1-9-1-2 on upper edge of brim. Removable metal band inside hat, ARCH-AM-2005-012 (Box 1)
  - Plug Ugly class of 1913. Decorated with shield of Aeronautical Reserve (189 N.Y.) on top; ME, a cat, an airplane around sides; string of female figures [similar to cut-out dolls] along the upperside of brim; Stanford University 1913 on underside of brim; John Heath on inside of hat, ARCH-AM-2005-010 (Box 1)
  - Plug Ugly hat (soft): '09 on top; zoology and Encina on sides; red ribbon trim, ARCH-AM-1993-11 (Box 1)
  - Plug ugly hat: 1914 on top, quad image on side, "Graphic Art" person painting on front and back, ARCH-AM-1993-07 (Box 1)
  - Plug Ugly with "S" on one side and "'05" on the other; red hat band with red feather. Button: rose superimposed over S, with red and white ribbons [probably of much later date than the Plug Ugly], ARCH-AM-2002-13 (Box 1)
  - Plug Ugly with drawings of locomotive engine with 00 on front, bag of coins, teller's window, Quad scene on top. "Frank Adams" written on inside.[Has drawings, but not much paint], ARCH-AM-2001-02 (Box 1)
  - Plug Ugly, 1909, ARCH-AM-1994-08 (Box 1)
  - Plugs: 1901,1905,1909,1910,1913, ARCH-AM-2000-074 (Box 1)
  - Pocket watch presented to DSJ on 60th birthday (1-19-11) by pioneer faculty, chain originally DSJ, with PhiBetaKappa Key, Cornell '72., ARCH-AM-1980-08 (Box 1)
  - Pocket watch won by Errol Campbell, '14, at the July 4 celebration at Schenley Park, for the 220 yards open., ARCH-AM-1984-05 (Box 1)
  - Political buttons for Eisenhower, Wilkie, and Humanity Legion Aid to China 1941, ARCH-AM-2004-025 (Box 1)
    025.1 "I LIke Ike" 025.2 Wilkie volunteers (3 items); 025.3 Win with Wilkie (2 items); 025.4 Wilkie Contributor; 025.5 Humanity Legion Aid to China California Rice Bowl Party 1941; 025.6 American flag (no text)
  - Polo shirt (navy blue) with "Cap and Gown" on left side and image of mortar board, ARCH-AM-2008-019 (Box 1)
  - portion of a t-shirt framed in plastic box: "OUT ON THE FARM gay and lesbian alliance at stanford" with line drawing of Segal statue. Red fabric with white letters, ARCH-AM-2000-014 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Anna Maria Lathrop, ARCH-AM-2000-021 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Anna Maria Lathrop, ARCH-AM-2000-022 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Asher Lathrop, ARCH-AM-2000-019 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of David and Anna Lathrop Hewes, ARCH-AM-2000-014 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Dyer Lathrop, ARCH-AM-2000-020 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Jane and Leland Stanford, ARCH-AM-2000-013 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Jane Lathrop Stanford; purple velvet frame, ARCH-AM-2000-037 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Jane Stanford, ARCH-AM-2000-016 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Jane Stanford, ARCH-AM-2000-017 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Leland Stanford, Jr. (painted on plaster or porcelain by Fr. Dresden); purple velvet frame, ARCH-AM-2000-035 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of man (BW), man with beard. oval, 46x36 cm. black wooden frame. o.d. 57x67, glass, ARCH-AM-2000-081 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of man in oil of water color. 26x19; Artist; S.J. Fleients Carlan. wood frame, glass. o.d. 75x56 cm, ARCH-AM-2000-084 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of man; photograph, 38x36 cm. in wooden frame with glass. o.d. 80x70 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-085 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Mark Hopkins (oil on board or linen?), in elaborate frame with gold-painted plaster leaf border. Frame: 15.75 x 17.5 in.; image 6 x 9.5 in., ARCH-AM-2005-018 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Mr. Mrs. Dyer Lathrop, ARCH-AM-2000-015 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Mrs. Dyer Lathrop (mother of Jane Stanford), ARCH-AM-2000-012 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Mrs. Dyer Lathrop; purple velvet frame, ARCH-AM-2000-036 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Thad Sigourney, ARCH-AM-2000-018 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, BW Photgraph, by Bradley Ruloson '93, S.F. Oval Format 76x66 cm., wooden frame 104x91 cm., under glass., ARCH-AM-2000-078 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Daivd Starr Jordan, 1913. 38"x50"in., ARCH-AM-2000-336 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Elizabeth Phillips Stanford- Leland's mother., ARCH-AM-2000-350 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, John Casper Branner, c. 1913. 48x40cm., ARCH-AM-2000-337 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Judge Samuel Lieb. 67x48cm., ARCH-AM-2000-335 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Mark Hopkins., ARCH-AM-2000-349 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, oil, David Starr Jordan, by Spencer Macky, 1922, framed. frame 110x92 cm, image 113x122 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-280 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, oil: Ray Lyman Wilbur, c. 1943, ARCH-AM-2000-338 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Senator Leland Stanford, Oval., ARCH-AM-2000-348 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Anna Maria Lathrop Hewes, ARCH-AM-2000-347 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Donald B. Tresidder, ca. 1950, ARCH-AM-2000-339 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: J. E. Wallace Sterlling, 1971, ARCH-AM-2000-341 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Josiah Stanford, Sr., ARCH-AM-2000-346 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Kenneth Pitzer, ca. 1970, ARCH-AM-2000-340 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Leland Stanford, Jr.; oil in gold frame, ARCH-AM-2000-345 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Mark Hopkins, ARCH-AM-2000-344 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Richard W. Lyman, ARCH-AM-2000-342 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Timothy Hopkins, ARCH-AM-2000-343 (Box 1)
  - Post Office Boxes, ARCH-AM-2000-108 (Box 1)
  - Poster (art work) cartoon, man at piano (on cardboard). 73x49 cm. Ink and pastel., ARCH-AM-2000-312 (Box 1)
  - Poster (art work) cartoon, man at radio microphone (on cardboard). 73x49 cm. Ink and pastel., ARCH-AM-2000-314 (Box 1)
  - Poster (art work) cartoon, man dressed as a king with V sign (on cardboard). 73x49 cm. Ink and pastel., ARCH-AM-2000-311 (Box 1)
  - Poster (art work) cartoon, man in football uniform (on cardboard). 73x49 cm. Ink and pastel., ARCH-AM-2000-313 (Box 1)
  - Poster board with examples of table finishes and upholstery materials and two photographs of furniture for the activities center, Graduate School of Business, Stanford University, [1970s from look of the furniture], ARCH-AM-2006-012 (Box 1)
  - Poster on cardboard. 56X36 cm. Blue and Gold, 1903, bu Jr. Class of Univ. of California., ARCH-AM-2000-154 (Box 1)
  - Poster; Driving the Golden Spike, ARCH-AM-2000-315 (Box 1)
  - Presented to Stanford University from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration. Flag and crew patch flown aboard space shuttle Columbia 1990, with photographs. Signed by G. David Low, Stanford class of 1983. 40.5 cm x 50.5 cm, ARCH-AM-1994-15 (Box 1)
  - Press pass for Gorbachev's talk, May 9, 1992 (#187), ARCH-AM-1995-06 (Box 1)
  - Pressboard binder from the Stanford Bookstore, ca. 1950 (originally with accn 2002-020). With LSJU seal embossed on lower right corner and embossed elaborate border for title area., ARCH-AM-2002-08 (Box 1)
  - Print of the Spencer Macky Portrait of David Starr Johnson, framed, with glass. Enscribed by Jordan. ("with kind regards"), ARCH-AM-1984-06 (Box 1)
  - Printing block (metal on wood), 2.5 x 1.5 inches, for the movie "Spirit of Stanford" 1942, ARCH-AM-2002-02 (Box 1)
  - Printing block for Jewel Fund bookplate: copper plate on wood block, ARCH-AM-2003-018 (Box 1)
  - Printing die - view of Mem Church through arch "Stanford Memorial Church" beneath, ARCH-AM-1981-14 (Box 1)
  - Printing dies of the University seal, the tree symbol, and the Stanford "S", ca. 1950; ARCH-AM-2009-015 (Box 1)
    9 dies of the University Seal, assorted sizes 2 dies of the tree symbol 1 die of the Stanford "S"
  - Printing plate (metal) for "Hail, Stanford Hail" (Arranged for male voices by Warren D. Allen), ARCH-AM-2003-010 (Box 1)
  - Printing plate for biographical information on Grayson N. Kefauver, with several sketches; signed "Stratton '35", ARCH-AM-2005-046 (Box 1)
  - Printing Plate; Stanford Library. 25X34X2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-187 (Box 1)
  - Printing plate: portrait of William D. Briggs, ARCH-AM-1992-04 (Box 1)
  - Printing plates for music (4); at least one is from the 1905 DECENNIAL OF STANFORD SONG (includes paper print from each one), ARCH-AM-1996-05 (Box 1)
  - Printing plates for text and illustrations of M. Bailey's book Seven Peas in the Pod, ARCH-AM-2002-11 (Box 1)
    boxes 1-12 are text plates (some with illustrations also); box 13 is illustration plates on wooden blocks
  - Proclamation signed by Governor Ronald Reagan regarding Transcontinental Railroad Centennial Day, May 10, 1969. Framed, ARCH-AM-2001-07 (Box 1)
  - Promotion materials for book "Stanford Sports", ARCH-AM-1983-08 (Box 1)
    1. T-shirt: tan, with football player "Stanford Sports" size 34-36, polyester, cotton 2. Button: 8x5.5cm with "Stanford Sports" and color photograph of football players (#10)
  - Purple and white striped scarf and unused "indecks Research Deck" (punch card system for sortable notes), ARCH-AM-2006-003 (Box 1)
    2006-003.01 scarf 2006-003.02 research deck
  - Quilt, approx. 10 x 10 ft; 1993, ARCH-AM-2008-006 (Box 1)
  - Quilts (12) made by HAAS students, 1994-2005, ARCH-AM-2006-037 (Box 1)
    Box 1: 2006-037.1 Class of 1994 2006-037.2 Class of 1995 2006-037.3 Class of 1996 Box 2: 2006-037.4 Class of 1997 2006-037.5 1998 2006-037.6 1999 2006-037.7 [untitled] 2000 Box 3: 2006-037.8 2001 2006-037.9 [untitled] 2002 2006-037.10 2003 2006-037.11 2004 2006-037.12 2005
  - Ransome concrete form - boards; discovered during 1997 renovation. 4.5 ft. x 5.5 ft., ARCH-AM-1997-014 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Dartmouth College LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.15 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Hood, University of California., ARCH-AM-2000-188.3 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Hood: Duke University LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.5 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Hood: Syracuse ScD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.2 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Hood: Univ. of Arizona LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.4 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: New York University LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.7 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Princeton univ. LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.12 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Scd. Western Reserve, ARCH-AM-2000-188.1 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Tusculum College LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.6 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Univ. of Chicago LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.8 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Univ. of New Mexico LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.11 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Univ. of Pennsylvania LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.16 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Univ. of Pittsburgh LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.14 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Univ. of Rochester LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.10 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Univ. of State of new York (Albany) LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.9 (Box 1)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, honorary degree hood: Yale Univ. LLD, ARCH-AM-2000-188.13 (Box 1)
  - Razor Strop. Used by Encina Barber, (19?, 16x6 cm. strop with metal end,), ARCH-AM-2000-118 (Box 1)
  - Red white ribbon with rosette used at dedication of Language Center building (Bldg 30) on 5/8/97, ARCH-AM-1997-006 (Box 1)
  - Red apron and ID tag from SULA book sale, circa 1995; ARCH-AM-2009-032 (Box 1)
    2009-032.1 red apron 2009-032.2 ID tag: "Book Sale Associate" in plastic holder with chain
  - Red balloon in plastic box. 9x6x5. Dated 7/8/76, balloon imprinted with Starts (Student Arts at Stanford)., ARCH-AM-2000-239 (Box 1)
  - Red cloth band with "STANFORD '54" [use unknown - not a hat band], ARCH-AM-1999-023 (Box 1)
  - Red felt "Stanford" banner with seal in right corner and "27" in left corner, ARCH-AM-1993-16 (Box 1)
  - Red felt banner with white trim and lettering, "Stanford" with seal taken into space by Sally Ride on the U.S. space shuttle Challenger, June 18-24, 1983., ARCH-AM-1984-09 (Box 1)
  - Red felt banner: "Stanford" in white letters, ARCH-AM-1990-001 (Box 1)
  - Red felt football (8 1/4" long) with white printed letters: "Stanford" and laces, ARCH-AM-1982-06 (Box 1)
  - Red felt pennant with "1937" in red letters. RETURNED TO CASPER 4/3/2002, ARCH-AM-2000-022 (Box 1)
  - Red foam Axe: Stanford Axe Committee Give 'Em The Axe, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-038 (Box 1)
  - Red knit athletic jersey, '01, ARCH-AM-2000-060 (Box 1)
  - Red leather pillow, ca. 1907 with fringe. Has block "S" in white leather pasted on and some flowers in white leather pasted on, ARCH-AM-1989-071 (Box 1)
  - Red men's tie, with hand painted "lil Injun" in white, ARCH-AM-2000-034 (Box 1)
  - red polo shirt, emblem: STANFORD NCAA 2001 SWEET SIXTEEN, ARCH-AM-2005-048 (Box 1)
  - Red ribbon and scissors used at grand re-opening of Green Library Bing Wing, October 12, 1999., ARCH-AM-1999-020 (Box 1)
  - red silk scarf - hemmed square with white "S" in center (15 in.), ARCH-AM-2007-023 (Box 1)
  - Red sponge axe with "Stanford Axe Commitee Give 'Em The Axe" and the Stanford S with superimposed tree., ARCH-AM-2002-09 (Box 1)
  - red sweater "1905" on chest, ARCH-AM-2002-18 (Box 1)
  - Red sweatshirt with "AXE" in white letters, ARCH-AM-2002-21 (Box 1)
  - Red wool blanket with embroidered "LSJU" in center; used by Pres. Wilbir in Encina dorm room., ARCH-AM-1980-06 (Box 1)
  - Red wool cheerleading sweater belonging to Chesley Douglas, cardigan style, ARCH-AM-1999-013 (Box 1)
  - Relief Bust of Ray Lyman Wilbur - 58x41 cm, "3rd Pres. of Stanford"(in 6' crate), ARCH-AM-2000-080 (Box 1)
  - Replica (mold?) of plaque for James Grant Fergusson, A.B. 1908, 2nd Lieutenant in the Eighth Black Watch, Killed in Action at Longueval France 14 July 1916. (23.5 x 18 in.) Mounted on plywood (36 x 31 in.), ARCH-AM-2006-014 (Box 1)
  - Replica of 1887 trowel from cornerstone laying - presented to James C. Gaither; with original box, ARCH-AM-1997-008 (Box 1)
  - Replica of 1887 trowel from cornerstone laying - presented to Lawrence V. Ryan 1991 (trowel is 94 of 100), ARCH-AM-2000-008 (Box 1)
  - Replica of 1887 trowel from cornerstone laying - presented to Michael H. Walsh; with original box, ARCH-AM-1997-009 (Box 1)
  - Replica of Gold Spike; 14x15 cm on stand made from old R.R. Tie., ARCH-AM-2000-238 (Box 1)
  - Replica of trowel used at S.U. cornerstone laying.; #1 of 100; w/ flannel bag., ARCH-AM-1995-12 (Box 1)
  - Reproduction of Portrait of Jane Stanford/ o.d. 115x100 cm. Tinted, gold frame., ARCH-AM-2000-260 (Box 1)
  - Research Corp. Award to Wm Martin Fairbank, ARCH-AM-1978-04 (Box 1)
  - Resolution, framed, Stanford Alumni of Hawaii; re Jane Stanford's death. 1905 (calligraphy). frame 45x31, image 39x26cm., ARCH-AM-2000-278 (Box 1)
  - Rhumbatron, ARCH-AM-1996-14 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon from luncheon at the White House Feb. 27, 1886: image of the White House on one end, Mrs. Stanford's name on the other. [Invitation for this event in SC 033b, Series 3, Box 1], ARCH-AM-2005-001 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon with artificial flowers, following written on individual streamers: Mr. Stanford California Apr. 28 '91. Unknown event/purpose, ARCH-AM-2004-023 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon: Stanford stadium marshall number 10 Stanford v. California Nov. 19, 1921, ARCH-AM-1993-09 (Box 1)
  - Ribbons of the Stanford Parlor No. 76 N.S.G.W., 1886 and ca. 1899, ARCH-AM-2004-016 (Box 1)